Register of the O. J. (Oliver Julian) Todd papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, 1908-1964
  - Moving picture film, 1927-circa 1932 (Box 63)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    For information on getting a use copy of motion picture films, please contact the Hoover Institution Archives
    - Undated, 35mm, B&W, fragment
    - Undated, 35mm, B&W, Mint farm?
    - Undated film fragment deaccessioned due to severe nitrate decomposition and health and safety hazards
    - Undated, 35mm, B&W, children riding a donkey
    - Undated, 35mm, color, Todd family?
    - Undated, 16mm, color, Todd children at school party
    - 1927, 16mm, B&W, Todd's Wedding Philippines
    - 1930, 16mm, B&W, Todd family
    - 1931, 16mm, B&W
    - 1931, 16mm, B&W, Doris and Elinor Todd swimming and riding a donkey at Peitaiho, China
    - 1932, 16mm, B&W, Todd children at Peitaiho and Peping, China
  - Photographs, 1926
    See also photographs of irrigation and dike work in progress, with dates and captions, in these series: AMERICAN NATIONAL RED CROSS and ASIA DEVELOPMENT COMPANY; CHINA INTERNATIONAL FAMINE RELIEF COMMISSION; and UNITED NATIONS RELIEF AND REHABILITATION ADMINISTRATION. See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, The Open Road in China, where photographs accompany the text.
    - 1908-1964
      - 6 prints, 7 duplicates and 1 negative depicting Todd only (Reel 78)
        Box/Folder 64: 1
      - 21 prints depicting Todd and others
        Box/Folder 64: 2
      - 1 print, 1 duplicate, 18 newspaper mats and 2 newspaper plates depicting Todd as congressional candidate
        Box/Folder 64: 3
      - 89 prints, 5 duplicates and 177 negatives depicting Robert Todd
        Box/Folder 64: 4
      - 48 prints and 3 duplicates depicting the Todd and Pendleton families
        Box/Folder 64: 5
      - 22 prints depicting friends and colleagues of Todd
        Box/Folder 64: 6
      - 16 prints depicting University of Michigan classmates of Todd. See also 7 oversize photos in Box 75
        Box/Folder 64: 7
      - 141 prints, 8 duplicates, 96 negatives and 16 post cards depicting work on the Hetch Hetchy water project, and Yosemite National Park
        Box/Folder 64: 8
    - 1909-1921
      - 48 prints and 93 negatives depicting Hetch Hetchy and Yosemite National Park
        Box/Folder 65: 1
      - 115 prints depicting Todd in military service
        Box/Folder 65: 2
      - 105 prints, 6 duplicates and 37 negatives depicting general views of China
        Box/Folder 65: 3
      - 43 prints and 3 duplicates depicting work on China's Grand Canal
        Box/Folder 65: 4-5
      - 243 prints, 10 duplicates and 135 negatives depicting civil engineering work for the Asia Development Company and the American National Red Cross in China. See also 2 oversize photos in Box 75.
        Box/Folder 65: 6-8
    - 1922-1938
      - Asia Development Company
        - 27 prints depicting views of Tsinan, China
          Box/Folder 66: 1
        - 12 prints and 10 duplicates depicting river work on the Yung Ting Ho
          Box/Folder 66: 2
      - China International Famine Relief Commission
        - 77 prints, 8 duplicates and 48 negatives depicting general views and phases of work on the Yellow River. See also 4 oversize photos in Box 75
          Box/Folder 66: 3
        - 3 prints depicting views of Canton, China
          Box/Folder 66: 4
        - 69 prints and 4 duplicates depicting views of the area of Honan and Yellow River flood damage
          Box/Folder 66: 5-6
        - 148 prints, 9 duplicates and 1 negative depicting river work in Chihli and the Tientsin region of Hopei Province
          Box/Folder 66: 7-9
        - 123 prints, 11 duplicates and 2 negatives depicting workers and equipment on the Yellow River in Hupeh Province
          Box/Folder 66: 10
        - 10 prints of views of Johel
          Box/Folder 66: 11
        - 4 prints, 2 duplicates and 1 negative depicting views of China's Great Wall at Kalgan
          Box/Folder 66: 12
        - 59 prints and 20 duplicates depicting the people and buildings of Kansu
          Box/Folder 66: 13
        - 89 prints, 8 duplicates and 3 negatives depicting Yellow River dike work at Kiangsi
          Box/Folder 67: 1
        - 10 prints depicting work at Kwangsi and Nanning
          Box/Folder 67: 2
        - 90 prints and 53 duplicates depicting people, buildings and scenery of Kweichow, China. Includes a print of Mr. Chow, Provincial Governor
          Box/Folder 67: 3
        - 95 prints and 4 duplicates depicting the Summer Palace, the Great Wall, buildings and statuary in the Peking area, and that city's irrigation system
          Box/Folder 67: 4
        - 3 prints and 1 duplicate depicting workers on the dike in Pu Chow County
          Box/Folder 67: 5
        - 3 prints, 2 duplicates and 2 negatives depicting a centrifugal pump at the Satochu Works, Saratsi
          Box/Folder 67: 6
        - 17 prints depicting ships in Shanghai harbor
          Box/Folder 67: 7
        - 164 prints, 46 duplicates and 24 negatives depicting scenes throughout Shansi Province, and the dams, bridges, gorges and channels of rivers which flow into the Yellow River: Fen Ho, Chin Ho, Sha Ho and the Sang Kan Ho
          Box/Folder 67: 8
        - 3 prints and 7 duplicates depicting the Governor of Shansi Province, Marshal Yen Hsi-shan, at his home, with Todd and Mr. L. H. Wang
          Box/Folder 67: 9
        - 166 prints and 9 duplicates depicting flood damage and subsequent dike repair work in the Shantung area, 1925 (Reel 79)
          Box/Folder 68: 1
        - 52 prints depicting river ice packs, the worker's camp and dike repair near Litsin, Shantung
          Box/Folder 68: 2
        - 48 prints and one duplicate depicting villages, and refugees in the flooded area of Li Chin, Shantung
          Box/Folder 68: 3
        - 88 prints, 20 duplicates and 142 negatives depicting dike closure work using kao-liang "sausages" in Shantung
          Box/Folder 68: 4
        - 128 prints and 20 duplicates depicting scenes throughout Shensi Province, and work on the Yellow River, the Yi Ho and the Wei Ho
          Box/Folder 68: 5
        - 60 prints and 30 duplicates depicting work on the Wei Pei Project, Shensi Province
          Box/Folder 68: 6
        - 62 prints and 8 duplicates depicting river work in Shensi Province
          Box/Folder 68: 7
        - 65 prints, 1 duplicate and 36 negatives depicting roads and a Fen Ho bridge in Shansi Province
          Box/Folder 69: 1
        - 172 prints and 22 duplicates depicting scenes of the Suiyuan area and the Saratsi Canal
          Box/Folder 69: 2
        - 65 prints and 14 duplicates depicting scenery and people along the Yangtze River in Szechuan Province
          Box/Folder 69: 3
        - 54 prints, 9 duplicates and 16 negatives depicting shipping on the Yangtze River
          Box/Folder 69: 4
        - 95 prints and 34 duplicates depicting scenery in Yunnan Province
          Box/Folder 69: 5
    - United States, Department of the Interior, Bureau of Reclamation, 1941
      Box/Folder 69: 6. 4 prints of a river in New Mexico.
    - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration, 1945-1947
      - 160 prints and 14 duplicates depicting men and machinery working on Yellow River dike repair
        Box/Folder 70: 1
      - 115 prints and 134 duplicates depicting river dike closure work in Honan Province
        Box/Folder 70: 2
      - 133 prints, 93 duplicates and 4 negatives depicting heavy equipment and workers effecting river dike closure in Honan
        Box/Folder 70: 3-4
    - Joint Commission on Rural Reconstruction, 1949-1951
      - 169 prints and 27 duplicates depicting scenes and the people of Taiwan
        Box/Folder 71: 1-2
      - 94 prints and 20 duplicates depicting work on Taiwan's irrigation systems
        Box/Folder 71: 3
      - 120 prints depicting scenes of Taiwan which show topography
        Box/Folder 71: 4
      - 74 prints and 4 duplicates depicting canals and adjacent farms and villages on Taiwan (Reel 80)
        Box/Folder 72: 1
      - 106 prints depicting creeks, canals, ponds, weirs and pumping projects on Taiwan
        Box/Folder 72: 2
      - 58 prints and two duplicates depicting workers on irrigation system projects
        Box/Folder 72: 3
      - 210 prints, 2 duplicates and 83 negatives depicting the Hsi Ho Dam Project, the Tsao-Kung Pumping Project and the work on the Chia-Nan and Tou Liu Canals
        Box/Folder 72: 4-6
      - 16 prints unidentified
        Box/Folder 72: 7
    - General
      Photographs on subjects of interest to Todd and photographs presented to him.
      - Canada. 21 prints depicting scenery at Banff and Lake Louise
        Box/Folder 73: 1
      - China
        - Chinese leaders. 21 prints depicting Chen-lun Chang, Hsueh-liang Chang, Tzo-lin Chang, Chiang Kai-shek, Yu-hsiang Feng, Yung-chang Hsu, Hu Hu, Yuan-hung Li, Ch'uan-fang Sun, Sun Yat Sen, Kun Tsao, Pei-Foo Wu, Hsi-shan Yen, Hueh-chung Yu, Shih-kai Yuan. See also oversize photos in Box 75: General Sheng Chen, Kuang-ti Ch'in, Hsi-cheng Chou, General Yu-hsiang Feng, Fu-ch'u Han
          Box/Folder 73: 2
        - Ming Tombs, Nanking. 16 prints, 7 duplicates and 11 negatives depicting statuary along the funeral path, 1925, 1927
          Box/Folder 73: 3
        - Mint farms. 48 prints and 6 duplicates depicting buildings and workers harvesting the crop in Kai Yuan and Tsing Hua, 1922-1933
          Box/Folder 73: 4
        - Salt wells at Tze tintsing, Szechuan. 20 prints and 11 duplicates depicting salt junks, water sluices, boiling pans, bales of salt, 1920, 1930
          Box/Folder 73: 5
        - Teng Family Cemetery. 6 prints, 13 duplicates and 6 negatives depicting ruins of the statuary, 1926
          Box/Folder 73: 6
      - United States
        - Clackamas River, Oregon. 59 prints and 16 negatives depicting work on a diversion dam, 1915, 1923
          Box/Folder 73: 7
        - Eugene, Oregon. 17 prints depicting construction on a water project
          Box/Folder 73: 8
        - Huntington Lake, California. 16 prints, 11 duplicates and 14 post cards depicting year-round work on a water project, 1923
          Box/Folder 73: 9
        - New York Aquaduct, Davis Bridge Dam, Vermont. 13 prints and 18 negatives depicting equipment at the dam, 1923
          Box/Folder 73: 10
        - Oak Grove Project. 4 prints depicting erection of a steel transmission tower, 1923
          Box/Folder 73: 11
        - Portland Canal. 15 prints depicting a power house, trestle and views of the canal, 1900, 1914
          Box/Folder 73: 12
        - Yellowstone National Park. 93 prints and 119 negatives depicting scenery
          Box/Folder 73: 13
        - Yuma, Arizona. 10 prints and 4 duplicates depicting the Colorado River at Laguna Dam, 1923
          Box/Folder 73: 14
    - Unidentified and/or undated, 72 prints, 11 duplicates, 100 negatives and 2 post cards
      Box/Folder 74: 1-4
    - Lists of photographs of his engineering assignments, numbered, described and dated by Todd
      Box/Folder 74: 5-10
    - Oversize
      Box 75. 23 prints depicting University of Michigan classmates of Todd; staff members of the Asia Development Company, American National Red Cross, and the China International Famine Relief Commission; and Chinese leaders.